{
  "questions": [
    {
      "answer": "Rashomon effect",
      "question": "What kind of story telling effect is used in the movie Mamangam?",
      "options": [
        "Blind Man and the elephant",
        "Nonlinear story telling",
        "Rashomon effect",
        "Neo-Noir"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Padayottam",
      "question": "First 70mm film in Malayalam.",
      "options": [
        "Thacholi Ambu",
        "Padayottam",
        "My Dear Kuttichathan",
        "Kireedam"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "GrandMaster",
      "question": "First Malayalam movie to release in Netflix",
      "options": [
        "Pulimurugan",
        "MadhuraRaja",
        "GrandMaster",
        "Pazhasshi Raja"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Koodevide",
      "question": "In which movie does Mammootty's character kills Rahman , because of the latter getting too much attention from Mammootty's character girlfriend?",
      "options": [
        "Koodevide",
        "Chilambu",
        "Mazhavilkoodaram",
        "Thammil Thammil"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Thalasthanam",
      "question": "Which movie marks the stepping stone for superstardom of Suresh Gopi?",
      "options": [
        "Commissioner",
        "Lelam",
        "Mafia",
        "Thalasthanam"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "News",
      "question": "Which is the debut movie of director Shaji Kailas?",
      "options": [
        "News",
        "Kilukkampetti",
        "Dr. Pashupathi",
        "Souhrudam"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Lucifer",
      "question": "Which among these movies are not Industrial hit in Mollywood?",
      "options": [
        "Hitler",
        "Drishyam",
        "Lucifer",
        "Rajamanikyam"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Mammootty",
      "question": "Which Malayalam Actor has Number of National Awards as Best Actor?",
      "options": [
        "Sathyan",
        "Mohanlal",
        "Mammootty",
        "Prem Nazir"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Rajamanikyam",
      "question": "Which Malayalam movie made Theatrical gross of 20 Crores for first time ?",
      "options": [
        "Narasimham",
        "Hello",
        "Rajamanikyam",
        "Classmates"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Drishyam",
      "question": "Which is first 50 Crores movie in Mollywood?",
      "options": [
        "Pulimurugan",
        "Pazhassiraja",
        "Drishyam",
        "Premam"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "5",
      "question": "How many Times did Adoor Gopalakrishnan won National award for Best Director?",
      "options": [
        "5",
        "8",
        "4",
        "2"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Teacher",
      "question": "What was occupation of Sreenivasan (Vijayan) in Movie ChinthaVishtayay Shyamala?",
      "options": [
        "Preist",
        "Don",
        "Principal",
        "Teacher"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "2",
      "question": "How many National Awards did Manichithrathaazhu won?",
      "options": [
        "8",
        "6",
        "4",
        "2"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Saamy",
      "question": "In Johny Walker Movie, who made Chandini addicted to Drugs?",
      "options": [
        "Bobby Varghese",
        "Didi",
        "Johny Varghese",
        "Saamy"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Rajan P Dev",
      "question": "In Movie Sethurama Iyer CBI, Who enacted role of Bahuleyan?",
      "options": [
        "Rajan P Dev",
        "Jagathy",
        "Mukesh",
        "Narendra Prasad"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Koothara",
      "question": "Movie in which Mohanlal acted as a Mermaid?",
      "options": [
        "Uncle Bun",
        "Appu",
        "Koothara",
        "Moonammura"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "2",
      "question": "How many times Mohanlal won National Award (Best Actor)?",
      "options": [
        "5",
        "2",
        "7",
        "1"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Both Aadu & Aadu 2",
      "question": "In which movie did Jayasuriya enacted role of Shaji Paappan ?",
      "options": [
        "Aadu",
        "Anyeshanam",
        "Aadu 2",
        "Both Aadu & Aadu 2"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "INSP",
      "question": "In Sandhesham movie, what is name of Political party Jayaram work for?",
      "options": [
        "INC",
        "KRD",
        "INSP",
        "BSP"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Chathutty",
      "question": "What is character name of Innocent in movie \"Varavelpu\"?",
      "options": [
        "Dineshan",
        "Chathutty",
        "Simon",
        "Kunjalikutty"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Nagamanikyam",
      "question": "In movie \"Anandbhadram\" what does Digambaran hunt for?",
      "options": [
        "Ananthan",
        "Bhadra",
        "Nagamanikyam",
        "Udavaal"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Seven Bells",
      "question": "What is name of musical instrument mentioned in movie \"Devadoothan\"?",
      "options": [
        "Five Rings",
        "Seven Bells",
        "Flute of Life",
        "SapthaSwaram"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Telephone Uncle",
      "question": "What is name of Mohanlal in movie \"OnnuMuthalPoojyamVare\"?",
      "options": [
        "Bhooth Uncle",
        "Manu Uncle",
        "Telephone Uncle",
        "IceCream Uncle"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Paasha",
      "question": "In Movie \"Vettam\" What is name of character enacted by Jagathy Shreekumar?",
      "options": [
        "Raman Kartha",
        "Hamza Koya",
        "Felix",
        "Paasha"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "7",
      "question": "How many Awards did movie \"Margam\" won in Kerala State Awards?",
      "options": [
        "3",
        "7",
        "9",
        "2"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "S Kumar",
      "question": "Who won Best Cinematographer Award in Kerala State Film Award 2004 for film Akale?",
      "options": [
        "S Kumar",
        "Little Swayamp",
        "Santhosh Shivan",
        "Shaji N Karun"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Arike",
      "question": "Which film didn't won National Awards for Best Film in Malayalam?",
      "options": [
        "Agnisakshi",
        "Akale",
        "Ore Kadal",
        "Arike"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Murali",
      "question": "Who enacted the role of jnanasekhara varma in Movie tiger?",
      "options": [
        "Suresh Gopi",
        "Siddique",
        "Rajmohan Unnithan",
        "Murali"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Commissionar",
      "question": "Which was the highest grossing Malayalam movie in year 1994?",
      "options": [
        "Commissionar",
        "Thenmavin Kombathu",
        "Kadal",
        "Vishnu"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Aa Rathri",
      "question": "Which is first Malayalam movie to gross 1 Crore ?",
      "options": [
        "New Delhi",
        "Aa Rathri",
        "Kilukkam",
        "Athiraathram"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "TG Ravi",
      "question": "Who enacted the role of Variyan Kunnathu Kunjahammed Haji in movie \"1921\"?",
      "options": [
        "A)Suresh Gopi",
        "Janardhanan",
        "Mammootty",
        "TG Ravi"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Priyadarshan",
      "question": "Who directed the Revolt scenes in movie \"Rakthasaakshikal Sindabad\"?",
      "options": [
        "Fasil",
        "Priyadarshan",
        "Hariharan",
        "Sibi Malayil"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "12",
      "question": "How many movies did Venu Nagavally worked as a Director?",
      "options": [
        "10",
        "7",
        "12",
        "None of Above"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Pazhassiraja",
      "question": "Which is first Malayalam movie to gross 40 Crores ?",
      "options": [
        "Drishyam",
        "Pazhassiraja",
        "Classmates",
        "Hello"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "New Delhi",
      "question": "Which is first Malayalam movie to get 1 Crore Share?",
      "options": [
        "Aa Rathri",
        "New Delhi",
        "Commissionar",
        "Chithram"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Odiyan",
      "question": "Which of below movie didn't do 100 Crore Total Business?",
      "options": [
        "Pulimurugan",
        "Mamangam",
        "Odiyan",
        "Madhuraraja"
      ]
    },
    {
      "answer": "Great Father",
      "question": "Which is first 50 Crores Grosser movie for Mammootty?",
      "options": [
        "Pazhassiraja",
        "Rajamanikyam",
        "Great Father",
        "Mamangam"
      ]
    }
  ],
"title": "Malayalam"
}